Register of the Sidney Hook papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1917-1990 (Boxes 31-101)
  - "Diderot's Great Legacy," New Leader, Jan. 2, 1961. Review of Denis Diderot, A Diderot Pictorial Encyclopedia of Trades and Industry. Printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "In Memoriam: S. M. Levitas," New Leader, Printed copy, and letters by William F. Buckley, Jr. and another, 1961, Jan. 16, 1961. (Folder 8)
  - "The Ethics of Controversy: Rejoinder to Julius Stone," Observer, March l8, Response to a reply by Stone to an article by Frank Knopfelmacher. Typescript, printed copy, letter, and printed copies of articles by Knopfelmacher, Stone and others, 1961 (Folder 9)
  - "The Death Sentence," New Leader, Printed copy, April 3, 1961. (Folder 10)
  - "Each Man for Himself," New York Times, April 9, 1961. Review of Ayn Rand, For the New Intellectual. Holograph, printed copy, printed comments by Nathaniel Branden, and correspondence with Philip M. Carden, Avery R. Johnson and others (Folder 11)
  - "The Couch and the Bomb," New Leader, Printed copy, printed copies of comments by Zbigniew Brzezinski and others, and letter, 1961, April 24, 1961. (Folder 12)
  - "Hook versus Stone," Bulletin, Response to a reply by Julius Stone to Hook's article "The Ethics of Controversy: Rejoinder to Julius Stone." Printed copy, printed copies of Stone's reply, printed copies of comments by others, and letters by Frank Knopfelmacher and another, 1961, April 26, 1961. (Folder 13)
  - "Growth of Pacifism Noted," New York Times, Letter to the editor. Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence, 1961, May 2, 1961. (Folder 14)
  - "A Reply," New York Times, Reply by Hook to letters to the editor by others commenting on Hook's article "Each Man for Himself." Typescript, printed copy, and printed copies of comments by others, 1961, May 7, 1961. (Folder 15)
  - "In League with the Kremlin," Saturday Review, May 20, 1961. Review of Sandor Voros, American Commissar. Typescript and printed copy (Folder 16)
  - "Escape from Reality," New Leader, Reply to comments by Erich Fromm on Hook's article "The Couch and the Bomb." Printed copy, and printed copy of Fromm's article, May 29, 1961. (Folder 17)
  - "Split Decisions," New York Times, July 23, 1961. Review of Wallace Mendelson, Justices Black and Frankfurter: Conflict in the Court. Printed copy (Folder 18)
  - "The Death Sentence," New York Law Forum, Contribution to a symposium on capital punishment. Correspondence with Hugh A. Bedau and others, 1961-1984, Aug. 1961. (Folder 19)
  - "Enlightenment and Radicalism," Encounter, Letter, 1961, Aug. 1961. (Folder 20)
  - "The New Revisionism," East Europe, Aug. 1961. Review of John Lukacs, The History of the Cold War. Printed copy and letter (Folder 21)
  - "Questions of Conformity," New Republic, Relates to Irving Howe. Holograph and typescript, Aug. 21, 1961. (Folder 22)
  - "For Stand at West Berlin," New York Times, Letter to the editor relating to Eric Kahler. Printed copy, Aug. 28, 1961. (Folder 23)
  - Letter to the editor, East Europe, Relates to comments by John Lukacs on Hook's article "The New Revisionism." Printed copy, typescript and printed copies of Lukacs' comments, and letter, 1961, Oct. 1961. (Folder 24)
  - "Western Values and Total War," Commentary, Debate with H. Stuart Hughes, Hans J. Morgenthau and C. P. Snow. Correspondence, 1961-1963, Oct. 1961. (Folder 25)
  - Speech, Interpretive summary of the Symposium on the Health Care Issues of the Nineteen Sixties. Typescript, printed copy, and letter, 1961-1963, Oct. 4, 1961. (Folder 26)
  - "Hegel and the Perspective of Liberalism," in Don C. Travis, ed., A Hegel Symposium, 1962. Printed copies (English and Italian), and letters by Meyer Schapiro and others, 1961-1963 (Folder 27)
  - "The Humanities and the Taming of Power," in The Role of the Humanities in Ordering a Peaceful World, 1962. Printed copy and correspondence, 1962-1963 (Folder 28)
  - Introduction to Raphael R. Abramovitch, The Soviet Revolution, 1917-1939, Printed copy, 1962. (Folder 29)
  - The Paradoxes of Freedom, 1962. Contract, reviews, and letters by C. J. Ducasse, Loren C. Eiseley, Arthur Krock and others, 1961-1987 (Folder 30)
  - "Political Ideology as a Factor of National Power," Lecture, National War College. Holograph outline and letter, 1962 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - "The Cold War and the West," Partisan Review, Contribution to a symposium. Printed copy, letter, and printed copies of contributions by Hannah Arendt, Irving Howe, and Dennis H. Wrong, 1962, Winter 1962. (Folder 2)
  - "Better Red than Dead, or Lord Russell's Guide to Peace," New York Times, Jan. 14, 1962. Review of Bertrand Russell, Has Man a Future? Typescript, printed copy, and letters by Henry Hazlitt and others (Folder 3)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, Reply to letters to the editor by Paul Goodman, M. Lincoln Schuster and others, relating to Hook's review "Better Red than Dead, or Lord Russell's Guide to Peace." Typescript, printed copy, typescript, galley and printed copies of letters by Goodman, Schuster and others, and correspondence, 1962, Feb. 18, 1962. (Folder 4)
  - "Un Homme et un Livre," Le Contrat Social, May-June 1962. Review of Raphael R. Abramovitch, The Soviet Revolution. Printed copy (Folder 5)
  - Review of Robert Tucker, Philosophy and Myth in Karl Marx, Slavic Review, Typescript, Sept. 1962. (Folder 6)
  - "Revisionism at Bay," Encounter, Holograph and typescript, Sept. 1962. (Folder 7)
  - "Le Rjve Communiste et la Rialiti," Le Contrat Social, Printed copy, Sept.-Oct. 1962. (Folder 8)
  - "Communism: What Lies Ahead," Nation's Business, Contribution to symposium. Typescript, printed copy, and letter, 1962, Oct. 1962. (Folder 9)
  - "Religious Liberty from the Viewpoint of the Open Society," Speech, 1st National Institute, National Conference of Christians and Jews Religious Freedom and Public Affairs Project, Washington, D.C. Typescript, printed copies (English and Italian), and letter, 1963, Nov. 1962. (Folder 10)
  - "The Map Was Redrawn to Make Man's Agony a Part of the Geography," New York Times, Nov. 11, 1962. Review of Martin Heidegger, Being and Time. Printed copy and letters (Folder 11)
  - "The Impact of Expanding Research Support on the Universities," Journal of Medical Education, Letter, 1963, Dec. 1962. (Folder 12)
  - "The Politics of Science Fiction," New Leader, Dec. 10, 1962. Review of Eugene Burdick and Harvey Wheeler, Fail- Safe. Printed copy, clipping, and correspondence with John Chamberlain, Alfred A. Knopf, Harry A. Overstreet, Edward Teller and others, 1962-1963 (Folder 13)
  - "A Reply," New York Times, Letter to the editor relating to letters to the editor commenting on Hook's review "The Map Was Redrawn to Make Man's Agony a Part of the Geography." Printed copy, and printed copies of the letters by others, Dec. 16, 1962. (Folder 14)
  - "How Should Communism be Taught in our Schools?" ca. 1963. Typescript, letter, and program announcement, 1962-1963 (Folder 15)
  - The Fail-Safe Fallacy, 1963. Booklet. Holograph, contract, reviews, and correspondence with Hunter Harris, Edward Teller and others, 1962-1977 (Folder 16)
  - Philosophy and History, (editor). Correspondence with W. H. Dray, Sidney Ratner and John Rawls, 1963 (Folder 17)
  - Statement in Science, Scientists, and Politics, Printed copy, 1963. (Folder 18)
  - "Religious Freedom in America," Cross Currents, Printed copy, Winter 1963. (Folder 19)
  - "Peace, Freedom and Survival," Speech, Ripon College, Holograph (incomplete), and correspondence, 1962-1963, Feb. 26, 1963. (Folder 20)
  - Introduction to speech by Ignazio Silone, Typescript, April 18, 1963. (Folder 21)
  - "Lord Monboddo and the Supreme Court," New Leader, May 13, 1963. Review of Hugo L. Black, One Man's Stand for Freedom. Printed copy, and correspondence with Erwin N. Griswold, Leon H. Keyserling and others (Folder 22)
  - "Do the People Rule and Can They?" New York Times, July 14, 1963. Review of Walter Lippmann, The Essential Lippmann. Typescript, galleys, printed copy, and letters by Lester Markel, Agnes E. Meyer and others (Folder 23)
  - "Why the United States Needs a Freedom Academy," Think, Printed copy and letters, 1963-1964, Sept. 1963. (Folder 24)
  - "Challenging Study: Challenge of Communism," New York Times Magazine, Galleys, printed copy, and correspondence, 1963-1964, Oct. 13, 1963. (Folder 25)
  - Untitled fragment, ca. Relates to the death of John Kennedy. Holograph, Nov. 1963. (Folder 26)
  - "Introduction to Ethics," Television lecture series. Course introduction, outlines, bibliography, and memorandum, 1963-1965, 1963-1964. (Folder 27)
  - Introduction to Walter Lippmann, A Preface to Morals, Typescript and letter, 1964 (Folder 28)
  - Law and Philosophy, 1964 (editor). Correspondence with Melvin M. Belli, Ilmar Tammelo, Richard Taylor and others, 1963-1965 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - "Teaching by Television," Mimeograph, and letters by Thomas Clark Pollock and another, 1964 (Folder 2)
  - "Religious Liberty and the Open Society," New York University Bulletin, Holograph (incomplete), typescripts, and printed copy, Winter 1964. (Folder 3)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Review of Books, Feb. 24, 1964 (date written). Relates to comments by Robert Brustein on Hook's booklet The Fail-Safe Fallacy. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - "Common Sense and Disarmament," Yale Political, Printed copy and typescript, Spring 1964. (Folder 5)
  - "Liberalism and the Negro," Commentary, Round table discussion with James Baldwin, Nathan Glazer and Gunnar Myrdal. Printed copy, March 1964. (Folder 6)
  - "Fulbright's Rights Stand," New York Times, Letter to the editor relating to J. William Fulbright. Typescript and correspondence, 1964, April 8, 1964. (Folder 7)
  - "Pornography and the Censor," New York Times, Typescript, printed copy, galleys of letters to the editor, and correspondence, 1964, April 12, 1964. (Folder 8)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Reply to a letter to the editor by J. A. Fabro in response to Hook's letter to the editor "Fulbright's Rights Stand." Typescript and letter, 1964, April 13, 1964 (Folder 9)
  - "A Reply," New York Times, Letter to the editor relating to letters to the editor by Robert W. Haney, Elmer Rice and others, commenting on Hook's article "Pornography and the Censor." Typescript, printed copy, printed copies of the letters to the editor by Haney, Rice and others, and letters, 1964, May 10, 1964. (Folder 10)
  - "The Cunning of History," New Leader, May 11, 1964. Review of Isaac Deutscher, The Prophet Outcast. Printed copy (Folder 11)
  - "Trotsky and Deutscher," New Leader, Letter to the editor relating to comments by Max Nomad on Hook's review "The Cunning of History." Printed copy, and printed copy of Nomad's comments, 1964, June 22, 1964. (Folder 12)
  - "There's More than One Way to Teach," Saturday Review, Mimeograph, printed copy, brochure, and letter, 1964, July 18, 1964. (Folder 13)
  - "Metaphysics and Historicity," History and Theory, Sept.-Dec. 1964. Review of Emil L. Fackenheim, Metaphysics and Historicity. Typescript and printed copy (Folder 14)
  - "Myth, Realities and Promise in Higher Education," Speech, State University College, Oswego, N.Y. Typescript, and program, Oct. 13, 1964. (Folder 15)
  - "A Search Here and Beyond," New York Times, Nov. 8, 1964. Review of Whittaker Chambers, Cold Friday. Typescript and printed copy (Folder 16)
  - "Common Sense and Peace," Yomiuri, Statement, Conference for the Promotion of World Peace, Tokyo, Nov. 1964. Typescript, typescript summaries of the conference, printed copy, and correspondence, 1963-1965, Nov. 14, 1964. (Folder 17)
  - "Faces of Betrayers," New York Times, Nov. 29, 1964. Review of Rebecca West, The New Meaning of Treason. Letters (Folder 18)
  - Introduction to Rebecca West, The New Meaning of Treason, Typescript, printed copy, and letter, 1965 (Folder 19)
  - " Plus or Minus," 1965. Notes and holograph, 1984 (Folder 20)
  - "Hegel Rehabilitated?" Encounter, Printed copy, galleys of comments by Shlomo Avineri and Z. A. Pelczynski, and letters by R. N. Berki and Harry Goldberg, and to Melvin J. Lasky, 1965, Jan. 1965. (Folder 21)
  - "Freedom to Learn but Not to Riot," New York Times Magazine, Typescripts, galleys, printed copy, clipping, typescript and printed copies of letter to the editor by others in response, and correspondence with Paul Kapiloff, Harvey Schechter, Ernest van den Haag, and others, 1965-1966, Jan. 3, 1965. (Folder 22)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Relates to comments by Elizabeth French on U.S. foreign relations. Typescript, Jan. 4, 1965 (Folder 23)
  - "Hegel: Penseur Liberal?" Le Contrat Social, Printed copy, Jan.-Feb. 1965. (Folder 24)
  - "Changing Values in Higher Education in a Changing Society," New York State Education, Printed copy and letter, 1965, Feb. 1965. (Folder 25)
  - "Defends Protests to Russia on Jews," New York Times, Letter to the editor in reply to Stephen Dunn. Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence with Moshe Decter and Michael Josselson, 1965, Feb. 13, 1965. (Folder 26)
  - "A New Portrait of Hegel," March 1965 (date written). Review of Walter Kaufmann, Hegel: Reinterpretation, Texts, Commentary. Holograph, typescript, letter, proof copy of Kaufmann's book, and notes (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - "Truth and Consequences," Partisan Review, Reply to review by G. S. Fraser of Diana Trilling's essay on Alger Hiss. Holograph, Summer 1965. (Folder 2)
  - "Reply to Dr. Oppenheimer," Denver Post, Relates to comments by Frank Oppenheimer on the Vietnamese conflict. Typescript, printed copy, printed copy of Oppenheimer's article, and correspondence with Edward J. Rozek and another, 1965, July 27, 1965. (Folder 3)
  - Letter to the editor, Partisan Review, (date written). Reply to G. S. Fraser's response to Hook's article "Truth and Consequences." Typescript and letter by Diana Trilling, 1965, Aug. 7, 1965 (Folder 4)
  - "Friends and Enemies," New York Times, Aug. 22, 1965. Review of Haakon Chevalier, Oppenheimer. Letter (Folder 5)
  - "The Conflict of Freedoms," Common Factor, Autumn Printed copy and letter, 1967, 1965. (Folder 6)
  - "Radicalism in America," New Leader, Sept. 27, 1965. Letter to the editor in reply to comments about Hook's views on communism by Christopher Lasch in his book The New Radicalism in America. Typescripts, proofs, printed copy, printed article by Lasch, typescript review of Lasch's book by Arthur Schlesinger, Jr., and printed copies of an exchange between Lasch and John P. Roche (Folder 7)
  - "Second Thoughts on Berkeley," Teachers College Record, Mimeograph, printed copy, clipping, and correspondence with Norman Cousins, Joseph Fontenrose, John K. Jessup, John L. Kelley, Gail Kennedy, Clark Kerr, Carl Landauer, Seymour Martin Lipset, Benson Mates, William Petersen, Thomas Clark Pollock, Leo Rosten, George N. Shuster, David S. Shwayder, Harold W. Stoke, Harold O. Voorhis and others, 1965-1967, Oct. 1965. (Folder 8)
  - Art and Philosophy, (editor). Advertisement and letters, 1966 (Folder 9)
  - "Man's Quest for Security: A Philosopher's View," in E. J. Faulkner, ed., Man's Quest for Security, Letter by Faulkner, 1965, 1966. (Folder 10)
  - "Marxism in the Western World," in Milorad M. Drachkovitch, ed., Marxist Ideology in the Contemporary World: Its Appeals and Paradoxes, 1966. Printed copy, clippings, and correspondence with Drachkovitch, Leopold Labedz, George Urban, and others, 1964-1967 (Folder 11)
  - "In Reply to Dr. Hutchins," Santa Barbara News-Press, Letter to the editor relating to the Vietnamese conflict. Typescript, printed copy, printed copies of Hutchins' comments, letters to the editor by others, and letters, 1966, Feb. 27, 1966. (Folder 12)
  - "U.S. Policy and Communism," Santa Barbara News-Press, Letter to the editor in reply to a letter to the editor by Merrill Ring commenting on Hook's letter to the editor "In Reply to Dr. Hutchins." Printed copy, and printed copy of Ring's letter, March 20, 1966. (Folder 13)
  - "Liberal Catholic Thought," Commentary, April 1966. Review of Michael Novak, Belief and Unbelief. Printed copy, and letters by Novak and another (Folder 14)
  - "Writer Buttresses His Previous Criticism of Tax-Exempt Center," Los Angeles Times, Letter to the editor in reply to comments by Harold Willens on the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. Printed copy, and printed copy of Willens' comments, April 4, 1966. (Folder 15)
  - Letter to the editor, Los Angeles Times, (date written). Reply to comments by Robert M. Hutchins on Hook's letter to the editor "Writer Buttresses His Previous Criticism of Tax-Exempt Center." Typescript, and printed copy of Hutchins' comments, April 19, 1966 (Folder 16)
  - "Hegel and His Apologists," Encounter, Printed copy, and typescript of reply by Shlomo Avineri, 1966, May 1966. (Folder 17)
  - "Social Protest and Civil Obedience," Speech, University of California, Santa Barbara. Mimeograph, program, clippings, and letter, 1966, May 5, 1966. (Folder 18)
  - "The Quest for Security, or Existentialism without Tears," Speech, City University of New York. Holograph (incomplete), and program, May 11, 1966. (Folder 19)
  - "Karl Marx's Second Coming," New York Times, Printed copy and correspondence, 1965-1973, May 22, 1966. (Folder 20)
  - "Neither Blind Obedience nor Uncivil Disobedience," New York Times Magazine, Printed copy and correspondence, 1966-1967, June 5, 1966. (Folder 21)
  - "Marx's Second Coming," Problems of Communism, Correspondence with Fred G. Lange, 1966, July-Aug. 1966. (Folder 22)
  - "Some Educational Attitudes and Poses," Harvard Educational Review, Printed copy, Fall 1966. (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - "Reflections on the University Law School," Symposium contribution commenting on Robert M. Hutchins' paper "The University Law School," Symposium on the Projection of an Ideal: The Law School of Tomorrow, Rutgers University Law School, Newark, N.J. Holograph, printed copy, program, clipping, and letter, 1966-1968, Sept. 9, 1966. (Folder 2)
  - "Lord Russell and the War Crimes 'Trial,'" New Leader, Typescript, printed copy, and letters by Brand Blanshard and others, 1966-1967, Oct. 24, 1966. (Folder 3)
  - "Liberties in Conflict," Book Week, Nov. 6, 1966. Review of Thomas I. Emerson, Toward a General Theory of the First Amendment. Holograph and printed copy (Folder 4)
  - "Lord Russell's 'Tribunal,'" New Leader, Letter to the editor relating to comments by Ralph Schoenman on Hook's article "Lord Russell and the War Crimes 'Trial.'" Typescript, printed copy, and printed copy of Schoenman's comments, 1966, Dec. 19, 1966. (Folder 5)
  - "The Democratic Challenge to Communism," Typescript, 1967. (Folder 6)
  - Human Values and Economic Policy, (editor). Letter, 1967 (Folder 7)
  - Religion in a Free Society, 1967. Reviews, agreement, and correspondence, 1966-1984 (Folder 8)
  - Untitled writing, Relates to radicalism. Typescript, 1967? (Folder 9)
  - "On the Couch," New York Times, Feb. 5, 1967. Review of Meyer A. Zeligs, Friendship and Fratricide: An Analysis of Whittaker Chambers and Alger Hiss. Holograph, typescripts, galleys of letters to the editor, and correspondence with Zeligs, Nora de Toledano, Isaac Don Levine, William L. Marbury, Meyer Schapiro and others (Folder 10)
  - "Mr. Hook Replies," New York Times, Letter to the editor in reply to comments on Hook's review "On the Couch." Typescript, March 19, 1967. (Folder 11)
  - "Fifty Years After," Problems of Communism, Printed copy, and letter by Martin F. Herz, 1967, March-April 1967. (Folder 12)
  - "The Symbols, Myths, and Rationale of Revolution," Speech, Symposium on Revolution, Central Washington State College, Ellensburg, Wash., April 22, 1967.
    - Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Folder 13)
    - Miscellany. Programs, press releases, and bulletins, 1965-1967 (Folder 14)
    - Panel transcripts. Mimeographs (Folder 15)
    - Text. Notes, typescript, and mimeograph (Folder 16)
  - "Lessons of the Hungarian 'October,'" Scope, Spring-Autumn Printed copy, 1967. (Folder 17)
  - "Philosophy and Democracy," Series of 15 lectures. Typescripts, July 24-Aug. 11, 1967. (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - "Crisis for White, Negro Leadership," Los Angeles Times, Printed copy and letters, 1967-1969, July 28, 1967. (Folder 2)
  - "Cruel Deception," New Leader, Letter to the editor relating to the Vietnam War. Printed copy, and letter to the editor by another, 1967, Aug. 14, 1967. (Folder 3)
  - "Is There a Legal 'Right' to Revolt?" Los Angeles Times, Printed copy, and correspondence with Howard J. Ehrlich and Adolph L. Reed, 1967, Aug. 15, 1967. (Folder 4)
  - "Fluff on the Sleeve of History," New Leader, Aug. 28, 1967. Review of C. P. Snow, Variety of Men. Typescript, printed copy, and letter (Folder 5)
  - "Social Protest and Civil Disobedience," Humanist, Galleys, printed copy, printed condensation, and correspondence, 1967-1969, Fall 1967. (Folder 6)
  - "The Human Costs of Revolution," Speech, Sixth International Conference on World Politics, West Berlin. Notes, typescript, mimeograph, printed copy, participant lists, schedule, and mimeograph copies of O. Anweiler, "Some Results of the Educational Development in the USSR 50 Years After the Revolution," F. C. Barghoorn, "Prospects for Soviet Political Development: Evolution, Decay or Revolution?" Masamichi Inoki, "Soviet Foreign Policy from the Asian Point of View," Roman Kolkowicz, "Heresy Enshrined: Idea and Reality of the Red Army," E. Kamenka, "Soviet Philosophy: 1917-1967," and R. C. Kwant, "Fifty Years of Interaction Between Philosophy and Politics," 1967, Sept. 1967. (Folder 7)
  - "Liberal Anti-Communism Revisited," Commentary, Printed copy and correspondence, 1967, Sept. 1967. (Folder 8)
  - "Fulbright's Colossal Gall," Providence Journal, Printed copy, and correspondence with C. J. Ducasse and others, 1967, Sept. 4, 1967. (Folder 9)
  - Letter to the editor, New Leader, Relates to comments by M. S. Arnoni on the Vietnamese conflict. Typescript, printed copy, printed copy of Arnoni's comments, and correspondence, 1967, Sept. 25, 1967. (Folder 10)
  - Letter to the editor, New Leader, Relates to a reply by M. S. Arnoni to Hook's letter to the editor of Sept. 25, 1967. Printed copy, and printed copy of Arnoni's comments, Oct. 23, 1967. (Folder 11)
  - Letter to the editor, Commentary, (date written). Relates to comments on Hook's article "Liberal Anti-Communism Revisited." Holograph fragments, typescript, and proofs of letters to the editor by Michael Parenti and Samuel Salzman, 1967, Oct. 26, 1967 (Folder 12)
  - "Thoughts on the October Revolution: The Human Cost," New Leader, Galleys and printed copy, Nov. 6, 1967. (Folder 13)
  - "Does Philosophy Have a Future?" Saturday Review, Typescript, printed copy, and letters, 1967-1968, Nov. 11, 1967. (Folder 14)
  - "A Right Way to Remedy a Wrong, a Wrong Way to Secure a Right," New York Times Magazine, Letter, 1967, Nov. 26, 1967. (Folder 15)
  - Contemporary Philosophy, 1968. Pamphlet. Printed copy, notes, and correspondence, 1966-1967 (Folder 16)
  - "Democracy," 1968 (date written; intended for publication in the Encyclopedia Americana). Holograph, typescript, contract agreement, and letters (Folder 17)
  - "The Ethics of Political Controversy and the Educational Crisis," in Don W. Parson and Will A. Kinkugel, ed., The Ethics of Controversy: Politics and Protest, Typescripts, printed copy, and letter, 1968 (Folder 18)
  - "Freedom and Intelligence," 1968. Reply to a review by Daya Krishna of Hook's book The Paradoxes of Freedom. Typescript, typescript copy of Krishna's review, and letter (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - "Human Rights and Social Justice," Speech, North Carolina State University, Raleigh. Printed copy, 1968. (Folder 2)